

LUIGI PINNA

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

 $\bigcirc \text{https://github.com/luigiPinna} \bigcirc \text{https://github.com/luigiPinnaAevo}$

PERSONAL PROFILE

I hold a diploma in computer science and a degree in business management. My passion for technology led me to become a full stack developer, with a primary focus on backend development. I have gained experience with various technological stacks, combining creativity and technical expertise.

Although I began my career in the economic and accounting sectors, I quickly shifted my professional path towards IT. This diverse background allows me to have a broader and more strategic view of projects, significantly contributing to the team's success.

EMPLOYMENT _

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

@ Aevoluta | 2024 - present

- Develop and maintain web applications using FastAPI (Python) for the backend and React or Vue for the frontend
- Design and implement RESTful APIs
- PostgreSQL for database management
- AI implementation with OpenAi APIs

BACKEND DEVELOPER

a Aevoluta | 2022 - 2024

- Backend development and API creation using FastAPI (Python) and PostgreSQL
- Software development across a multitude of projects, focusing on data processing and automation
- RPA (Robotic Process Automation) and backend solutions with Python
- UiPath automation development

IT & MARKETING

@ ElleDi | 2020 - 2021

- Managed Front and Back Office operations, optimizing processes with CRM and ERP software.
- Performed data analysis and accounting, utilizing spreadsheets to track and report financial metrics.
- Supported digitalization initiatives by transitioning paper records to digital formats and improving data accessibility

EDUCATION _

THE NET VALUE

Full Stack Developer - 03/2021 - 11/2021

- Structured programming with $\ensuremath{\text{C}}$ language.
- Database management, data modeling and SQL.
- Backend-side object-oriented programming: Java and SpringBoot, C# and DotNet, Php and Laravel with respective final projects.
- Web-oriented development: Javascript, Typescript with Angular. Basics of React.
- Web app design: Rest API integration for a microservices-oriented architecture, realization of stateless and scalable microservices, employing modularization inherent in the Angular framework for responsive and performant web applications.

 Markup and style languages: Html, Css, Bootstrap.
- Tools: Postman, Git, GitHub, Trello, Notion.

UNIVERSITY OF CAGLIARI

Single course managerial economics - 2020/21

- Big Data and analytics for banking management
- Human resource management
- Management of family businesses

UNIVERSITY OF CAGLIARI

Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration and Management, 2019

Main areas of interest:

- Financial Mathematics
- Corporate Finance
- Private, commercial law

ITIS M. GIUA - CAGLIARI

Diploma in Computer Science

- Fundamentals of Computer Science
- Systems and networks
- Software and web development

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Core competencies in Python and SQL
- Front end stack: React, Angular
- Python frameworks: Fast API and Flask. Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, sqlAlchemy and Pydantic.
- CRUD experience with Java; Spring and Spring Security (JWT).
- Frontend experience with Angular and React.
- Use of Rest API, MVC, and Web API.
- Knowledge of CRUD operations in various programming languages.
- Experience with relational databases: Postgres and Oracle.
- Use of tools such as PowerBI, Postman and GitHub.
- Experience in Al: use of OpenAl API, image generation and prompt creation with GPT.
- Code management and versioning with Git.

OTHER SKILLS ___

- Ability to analyze complex technical information
- Ability to analyze, design and implement database structures (sql, Oracle)
- Attention to detail
- Clean code orientation
- Excellent problem-solving skills

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Advanced Google Analytics | Google (2020)
- Digital marketing Foundations | Google (2019)
- English level B2
- Driving license B
- Nautical Driving license
- Lifeguard certification

SOFT SKILL

- Team working
- Results orientation
- Adaptability
- Logical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Autonomy

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS_____

- Sports and fitness enthusiast: I regularly exercise in the gym, running and various sports. I am always looking for new personal challenges and love to maintain an active and healthy lifestyle.
- Sea and surfing: Boat license holder and sea enthusiast. Every summer I dedicate time to sailing and practice surfing, finding in contact with nature a way to regenerate myself.
- Technology and innovation: I maintain a constant interest in the latest technology and am particularly interested in startups with high innovation potential.

CONTACTS____

uigipinna 3@gmail.com

in LinkedIn: @luigipinna

Phone: +39 3406852842

https://luigipinna.com